listia.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy - Listia.com Auctions for Free Stuff

This is the Privacy Policy for the **listia.com** web site, apps, features, and all site-related services (collectively, the "Service"). This Privacy Policy describes the information we collect, how it may be used, with whom it may be shared, and your choices about such uses and disclosures. By using our Service, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

We can be reached via email at (admin @ listia.com) 

**Our legitimate interests:**

We process your information in pursuance of our legitimate interests, including: 

Providing and improving the Service. We do so as it is necessary to pursue our legitimate interests of providing and developing the Service to our users on a continuous basis; and   
Keeping the Service safe and secure. We do so as it is necessary to pursue the legitimate interests of Listia and its users in ensuring the Service is secure, and to protect against fraud, spam and abuse, etc. 

**Information we collect about you:**

Depending on your use of the Service, we may collect and process certain information including: 

Information that you provide through forms on the Service such as your name, username, email address, password, physical address, telephone number, gender, and birthday;   
Information you provide to third parties for payment processing or identity verification purposes. Listia partners with third parties (such as Stripe and Onfido) for payment processing and identity verification and the information you provide is collected and used by those third parties in accordance with their privacy policies. Listia does not store this information;   
Information about your activity on and interaction with the Service including use of our mobile apps. Information such as your IP address, device ID, the type of device, the type of browser and language, access times, the content of any cookies that your browser previously accepted from us, and your actions using the Service. To better understand the needs of our users and to help protect our users from fraud we may occasionally match such information with your account;   
Information that you submit on the Service in the form of comments, feedback, messages to other users, and listing information; and   
If you choose to sign up or connect with your Facebook credentials, Listia will receive your email address associated with your Facebook account and also request permission to access your name, profile picture, friend list, gender, and age range. These permissions are governed by Facebook’s privacy policy and can be managed through your Facebook privacy settings. 

We collect aggregate information on what pages consumers access or visit, information volunteered by the consumer, such as survey information and/or site registrations. 

**How we use the information we collect:**

The information we collect is used to keep your account secure, provide our Service, improve the content of our Service, customize the content and/or layout of our Service for each individual visitor, notify consumers about updates to our Service, and used by us to contact consumers for marketing purposes. 

With respect to cookies: We use cookies to store visitors preferences, record session information, such as items that consumers add to their shopping cart, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, record past activity at a site in order to provide better service when visitors return to our site, customize Service content based on visitors' browser type or other information that the visitor sends. 

Notwithstanding anything else in this policy, we or a data partner we have engaged may collect and store a unique identifier matched to your mobile device, in order to deliver customized ads or content while you use applications or surf the internet, or to seek to identify you in a unique manner across other devices or browsers. In order to customize these ads or content, we or a data partner may connect de-identified demographic or other data about you (received from third parties) either to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, or to data passively collected from you, such as your device identifier or IP address. 

If you do not want to receive email from us in the future, please let us know by sending us email at the above address or unsubscribing from your account settings. 

If you supply us with your postal address on-line you will only receive the information for which you provided us your address. 

Persons who supply us with their telephone numbers on-line will only receive telephone contact from us with information regarding orders they have placed on-line. 

**Sharing of your information:**

When you create an account, the following information is shared publicly: 

The username you choose, account creation date, and last login date;   
Comments, feedback you leave, and feedback you receive on listings; and   
Listings, listing information and details for open and completed listings. 

The following information is not shared publicly: 

Information associated with your profile such as your name, email address, password, telephone number, gender, and birthday;   
Information associated with your activity such as your IP address, device ID, the type of device, the type of browser and language, access times, and the content of any cookies that your browser previously accepted from us; and   
Payment processing information and identity verification information. 

When you purchase an item from another user that requires items to be shipped, we will share your physical address with the seller at your request. 

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain information when you visit our web site or mobile apps. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other web sites or mobile apps in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie, third party web beacon or tracking pixel on the web site, mobile apps or within emails to collect this information. We may also share aggregated, non-personal information, or personal information, such as your email address, solely in hashed, non-human readable form, with third parties, including partners and advertisers. Our partners use this information to recognize you across different channels and platforms over time for advertising, analytics, attribution, and reporting purposes. 

To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit: 

We also use Google Analytics data and the DoubleClick cookie to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to your website. You may opt out of the DoubleClick cookie by visiting the Google advertising [opt-out page](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads) or you may opt out of Google Analytics by visiting the Google Analytics [opt-out page](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). For further information, consult the privacy policies of: 

www.conversantmedia.com   
www.google.com   
www.facebook.com 

We also may disclose your information, including personal information in response to a subpoena or similar investigative demand, a court order, or a request for cooperation from a law enforcement or other government agency; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases, we may raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us. 

**Retention:**

We will retain your information as long as your account is active, as necessary to provide you with the Services or as otherwise set forth in this Policy. If you would like to delete your account please submit a support ticket [here](https://help.listia.com/hc/en-us/requests/new). 

We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

**Email and mobile notifications:**

We will send you email relating to your listings and transactions on Listia. You may also receive certain marketing email communications which can be managed in your account settings page under Notification Settings. 

Mobile notifications that you receive on our mobile apps can be managed via the app in Settings. 

**Your choices about the collection and use of your information:**

From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our web site to notify you of these changes and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our web site periodically. Customers may prevent their information from being used for purposes other than those for which it was originally collected by emailing us at the above address. 

You have the right to access and correct, or delete your information at any time on your account page where you can view and make changes to most of your information immediately. Upon request we provide site visitors with access to contact information (e.g., name, address, phone number) that we maintain about them and a description of information that we maintain about them. Consumers can access this information by emailing us at the above address. Consumers can have this information corrected by sending us email at the above address. 

**EU members’ rights:**

Users residing in certain countries, including the EU, are afforded certain rights regarding their personal information. Except where an exception or exemption applies, you have the right to access, update, delete, or download your information, as well as the right to restrict and object to certain processing of your information. You can access, update, and delete much of your information by logging in and going to your account settings page. We may retain certain information as required by law or as necessary for our legitimate business purposes. You can request a downloadable copy of your personal data by emailing us at the above address. 

Should you wish to raise a concern about our use of your information (and without prejudice to any other rights you may have), you have the right to do so with your local supervisory authority or the United Kingdom Information Commissioner's Office. 

**Security:**

We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site. 

**Privacy information cotact:**

If you feel that this site is not following its stated information policy, you may contact us at: 

Listia Inc.   
ATTN: Privacy   
2010 El Camino Real #231   
Santa Clara, CA 95050-4051   
Email: admin @ listia.com 

Last Updated: May 24, 2018 

BBB Profile: [Listia Reviews](http://www.bbb.org/sanjose/business-reviews/internet-shopping/listia-in-mountain-view-ca-1000004929)
